Finding Aid for the All World Hebrew Central Organization records, 1943-1947 LSC.1646
UCLA Library Special Collections
All World Hebrew Central Organization records
1943-1947
UCLA Library Special Collections
All World Hebrew Central Organization
LSC.1646
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
The All World Hebrew Central Organization was a Hebraic organization whose mission was to protect and defend the interests of the Hebrew people. Collection includes correspondence, clippings, and sheet music related to the All World Hebrew Central Organization located in Los Angeles, CA.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Transferred from UCLA Music Library, 1987.
Custodial History
Originally received by the UCLA Music Library with a collection of music scores and sketches of composer Alfred Kaufman.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 994621703606533
History
The All World Hebrew Central Organization was founded in 1935 in Berlin, Germany, as a political Hebraic organization whose mission was to protect and defend the interests of the Hebrew people anywhere in the world.
Scope and Content
Collection consists of correspondence, clippings, and sheet music related to the All World Hebrew Central Organization located in Los Angeles, CA. Also includes clippings about various musicians.
Jews -- Societies, etc. -- Archives.; All World Hebrew Central Organization--Archives
- Franchise Commissioner Sacramento, 1943-1944, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Correspondence, documents re State of California Office of Franchise Tax Commisioner, Sacramento
- Hebrew Question Correspondence, 1943-1944, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Correspondence to various members of the United Nations re a voting ballot dealing with the Palestine and Hebrew question
- Memorandum of claim of the All World Hebrew Central Organization, 1945, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Memorandum of claim of the All World Hebrew Central Organization re the Jewish Race (4 copies) and related correspondence; Correspondence, news clippings re minority groups
- Hebrew congress/War Refugee Board correspondence, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Includes 8x10 photograph of 3 unidentified people.
- Articles of Incorporation and related material, 1939, 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Correspondence, documents, newsclippings re Hebrew recognition; copy of Berliner Morgenspost Nr. 33.
- Music sheets, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Music sheets for "Nina," "Song of Liberation New Hebrew Anthem," "Look in the Mirror and Find the Real," by Elisabeth Kaplan and A.A. Kaufman and unidentified song.
- United States-Hebrew Steamship Company, 1944-1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Financial documents re Hebrew Steamship Company, Inc.
- Report of daily organizational activities of Kaya Malamadoff in regards to collection of Ship-fun lists, 1944, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Includes copy of United nations Delegations to the United Nations, June 1947
- Miscellaneous news clippings, 1939; not organized (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Radio correspondence, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Correspondence to various radio stations re use of the word "Hebrew" versus "Jew"
- Secretary of State, Sacramento, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Correspondence with Honorable Frank Jordan, Secreatary of State of California re Articles of Incorporation and related materials
- H.K. Travers State Department Washington, D.C., 1943-1945 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  Correspondence with Howard K. Travers re various Hebrew issues; includes pamphlet entitled "Aims and Orgin of the All world Hebrew Central Organization;" includes correspondence with Haorld L. Ickes and Senator Wagner